-Hey.
-Hi.
- 뭐하는 거야?
- 소파를 이리 옮기려고
-What are you doing?
-I was thinking of moving the couch.
그걸 왜 옮겨?
Why would you want to do that?
그래야 내가 앉을 자리가
생길 거 아냐
So there'd be a decent place
for me to sit?
- 앉을데 있잖아
- 네 무릎 말고
-Rach, there is a decent place.
-And your lap does not count.
- 어서, 좀 도와 줘
- 안 돼, 안 돼
-Come on, help me move this.
-No, no, no.
- 안 된다고?
- 안 돼
-No?
-No.
로지타 못 옮겨
Rosita does not move.
뭐라고, 로지타?
I'm sorry. Rosita? As in..?
'로지타는 절대 못 옮겨'
As in "Rosita does not move."
의자 하나 갖고
왠 난리야?
It's just a chair.
What's the big deal?
여기서 화장실과
부엌까지의 거리도 같고
It's the exact equal distance
from the bathroom to the kitchen...
스티비한테 빛도 반사되지
않는 완벽한 각도란 말야
and it's at an angle where you
don't get any glare coming off Stevie.
TV이름이 스티비야?
Stevie the TV?
- 불만있냐?
- 아니
-Is there a problem?
-No.
알게 뭐야?
What does he know?
자, 로지타
우리 여자들끼리 힘을 모으자
Come on, Rosita.
Us chicas gotta stick together.
성깔하곤!
You bitch!
The One Where Rosita Dies
오빠
Hey, Ross?
부동산 광고난을 봤거든
I checked the real estate section.
이거 좀 봐
Look at this.
우리 집 같이 생겼네
Looks like Mom and Dad's house.
나무 가지 부러진 것도
똑같아
Even has a tree
with a broken limb out front.
그리고 창문있는 다락방...
And the window in the attic...
맙소사!
Oh, my God!
창문있는 다락방이
어떻게 됐는데?
What happened
to the window in the attic?
- 어떻게 집을 파실 수 있지?
- 우리한테 말도 안하고
-I can't believe they're selling it.
-And they didn't tell us.
창문있는 다락방이
어떻게 됐냐니까?
What happened
to the window in the attic?
I'll buy you a new one, okay?
새 의자 사줄게
We'll go to the store and get you
a new chair right now.
가게에 가서
당장 새 걸로 사자
아직 온기도 안 식었어
She's not even cold yet.
로지타도 네가 빨리
극복하길 바랄 거야
Wouldn't Rosita have
wanted you to move on?
항상 네 안락함을
최고로 생각했잖아
I mean, you know, she did always
put your comfort first.
그건 그래
That's true.
우리가 자란 집을
더 이상 못 보다니
I can't believe we have to say goodbye
to the house we grew up in.
생판 모르는 사람이
내 방에 살거아냐
Man, some stranger's gonna be
in my room.
그래도 15년이나
신전처럼 모셔뒀잖아
For 15 years they kept it
as a shrine to you.
이제 벨벳 공단을
치울 때도 됐지
It's time the velvet ropes came down.
네 방도 한 동안
그대로 뒀잖아
They kept your room a while.
나 나간 지 20분만에
체력단련실로 만드셨어
Please! Dad turned my room into
a gym 20 minutes after I moved out.
선탠 침대하고 속옷 잡지만
잔뜩 넣어뒀으니
I gotta say, a tanning bed and a stack
of Victoria's Secret catalogs?
체력단련실도 아니지
Not a gym.
- 엄마, 아빠도 널 사랑하셔
- 오빠만큼?
-Come on. You know they love you.
-As much as they love you?
나 태어나기 전엔 엄마가
불임인 줄 아셨대잖아
They thought she was barren
until I was born. It's not my fault.
I hate this year.
올해 너무 싫다
What's wrong with this year?
올해가 어때서?
벌써 2월인데 마사지
손님도 둘 밖에 없었고
It's February and I've only
given two massages...
팁도 얼마나 짜게 주던지...
and they were both horrible tippers.
나랑 오빠잖아
That was me and Ross.
아, 그랬지
Oh, that's right.
현금이 필요하면
If you want some extra cash...
내 친구처럼
텔레마케팅 일 해봐
some college friends made
good money doing telemarketing.
지난 번 전화 일보단
낫겠지
It'd be better than the last
telephone job I had.
'때려줘요'란 말
안해도 될 테니
I probably won't have to say
"spank" as much.
What?
뭐라고?
Oh, yeah, like you never called.
왜, 넌 안 해봤냐?
아주 쉬워요
여기 매뉴얼을 보고
This is very easy.
You read from the script...
토너를 가능한
많이 팔면 돼요
and try to sell as much
toner as you can.
좋아요, 할 수 있어요
Okay, I can do that.
그나저나
사무실 맘에 드네요
By the way, I love my office.
- 연습 한 번 해보죠
- 좋아요
-Why don't we do a trial run?
-Oh, okay.
좋아요
All right.
안녕하세요, 엠파이어
사무용품의 피비입니다
Hi, this is Phoebe
from Empire Office Supplies.
- 구매담당자 부탁합니다
- 제가 구매 담당자인데요
-Can I speak to your supply manager?
-I'm the supply manager.
토너가 필요하신가 해서
전화 드렸습니다
I'd like to talk
about your toner needs.
필요 없습니다
We don't need any.
귀찮게 해드려 죄송합니다
안녕히 계세요
Okay, sorry to bother you. Bye-bye.
정말 쉽네요
Yeah, you're right. This is easy.
Okay. What was wrong with that call?
좋아요, 어디가 잘못됐죠?
Oh, well, all right.
아, 맞아요
No offense,
but you were kind of rude.
죄송하지만
좀 딱딱거리시던데요
They always say they
don't need toner. That's okay.
항상 토너가 필요없다고
하지만 괜찮아요
Whatever they say, you can find the
answer to it, here in the script.
여기 매뉴얼에 대답이
다 나와 있거든요
So I think you're ready to sell toner.
이제 토너를 팔
준비가 됐겠죠
-Do you have any last questions?
-No.
- 마지막으로 질문 있어요?
- 아뇨
Wait, yes, I do have one question:
잠깐만요, 질문 있어요
What is toner?
토너가 뭐죠?
Joey?
조이?
Joe?
Full bag?
뜯지도 않았네
Beer's still cold.
맥주도 아직 차고
Something terrible
must have happened here.
틀림없이 아주
나쁜 일이 생긴 거야
Oh, no, no, no!
아냐, 안 돼, 안 돼!
Stevie, I was never here.
스티비,
나 여기 안 온거다
- 아버지?
- 여기 있다!
-Dad?
-I'm here!
- 안녕하세요
- 그래
-Hey.
-Hi.
너희들이 나 일하는 거
보던 때가 엊그제 같은데...
Seems like just yesterday you guys
used to come out to watch me work.
집을 파신다니
너무 서운해요
We can't believe
you're selling the house.
새 가족이 여기서
살게 되겠지
Time for a new family
to start here.
집 사는 사람들이
분수대 금간 것과
I hope their check clears before
they find the crack...
지붕에 석면 있는 걸
눈치 못 채야 할 텐데
in the foundation
and the asbestos in the ceiling.
우리 물건 챙겨서
빨리 나가자
Let's grab our stuff and
get the hell out of here.
- 너희 물건 둘 데가 없다
- 괜찮아요
-Sorry we can't store your things.
-Oh, it's okay.
저희 걸 볼 생각하니
흥분돼요
I can't wait to see everything again.
여기 뭐가 있는지
모르겠다만
I don't know what's down here.
다락에 장난감 오븐이
예닐곱 개 있더라
But there are six or seven
Easy-Bake Ovens in the attic.
식당 놀이 좋아했는데
I used to love to play restaurant.
'안 익은 반죽 먹기'
만큼은 아니었지
Not as much as you loved to play
"uncooked batter eater."
그럼 전구로 빵 굽는 걸
기다리란 말야?
You can't expect a child to wait
for a light bulb to cook brownies.
네 상자는 여기 있다
So I think your boxes are over here.
신난다
Oh, great.
Hey...
아버지, 이거 누구 담배예요?
whose cigarettes are these?
모르겠다
I don't know.
엄마 거겠지
They must be your mother's.
엄마한테 묻지 마라
내가 버릴 테니까
But please, please don't ask her.
I'll throw these away.
신난다! 아빠
내 성적표요
Cool! Dad, my report cards!
이것 좀 봐요
Hey, check this out.
수학 '수' 과학 '수'
역사 '수' 체육...
Math, "A." Science, "A."
History, "A." Gym...
돌 광택기다!
My rock polisher!
- 이런
- 왜요?
-Uh-oh.
-What?
봄마다 창고에
물차는 거 알지?
You know how the garage
floods every spring?
집을 어떻게
팔 생각이세요?
How are you ever gonna sell
this place?
나도 모르고
모니카 상자를
I think I accidentally
used Monica's boxes...
포르셰 자동차
물 막이로 썼구나
to keep the water away
from the Porsche.
이런, 아버지
Oh, no, Dad. Dad?
어떻게...
What the..
이런, 하나도
쓸 수 없게 됐네!
Oh, God.
Everything's ruined!
모니카 엄청 속상해 하겠어요
Dad, she's gonna be crushed.
너도 몰래 담배 피우니?
You don't secretly smoke, do you?
아뇨
No.
너희 엄마는 그런가 보다
So it's just your mother then.
안녕하세요, 엠파이어
사무용품의 피비입니다
Hi. This is Phoebe
from Empire Office Supplies.
구매 담당자와
통화할 수 있을까요?
Can I speak to your
supply manager, please?
얼이라고요, 고마워요
Earl. Thanks.
안녕하세요, 엠파이어
사무용품의 피비입니다
Hi, Earl. This is Phoebe
from Empire Office Supplies.
토너가 필요하신가 해서
전화 드렸어요
I'd like to talk to you
about your toner needs.
필요없어요
I don't need any toner.
그렇지만 이 가격엔
누구나 토너가 필요하죠
I hear what you're saying, but at
our prices, everyone needs toner.
난 아니에요
Not me.
이유를 물어도 될까요?
May I ask why?
이유를 알고 싶어요?
You want to know why?
이유를 알고 싶다고요?
물론이죠
I surely do.
좋아요
Okay.
난 자살을 할거니까
I don't need any toner...
토너가 필요없어요
because I'm gonna kill myself.
토너가 떨어져서
그러시나요?
Is that because you're out of toner?
Okay, so no toner today.
Thanks anyway. Bye-bye.
오늘은 토너 필요없어요
고마워요, 그럼
잠깐만요! 끊지 말아요
저랑 얘기 좀 해요
Wait, wait! I can't let you hang up.
Just please talk to me.
글쎄요...
Well...
오늘 할 일은 하나 뿐이죠
I only had one thing to do today.
오늘 할 일
'자살하기'
뭐 잠시 미뤄도 되겠죠
I guess I could push it back.
네, 왜 자살하려고
하세요?
Yeah. Now, why do you
want to kill yourself?
이 의미없고 지겨운 일을
10년이나
I've been working for 10 years
now at this...
해오고 있는데
meaningless, dead-end job...
아무도 내 존재조차도
모른답니다
and nobody here
even knows that I exist.
챈들러, 너니?
Chandler?
뭐라고요?
I'm sorry?
저기요
Look...
사람들이 당신
존재를 알 거예요
I'm sure that people know
you exist.
그럴까요?
내 책상 주위엔
Oh, yeah? I work in a cubicle...
사람들이 넘쳐나는데
surrounded by people.
지금 자살한다고 5분이나
통화를 하고 있는데
I've been talking to you for five
minutes now about killing myself...
아무도 쳐다보지도 않아요
잠깐만요
and no one's even looked up
from their desk. Hang on.
이봐, 나 좀 봐
Hey, everybody...
나 자살할 거야
I'm gonna kill myself.
아무 반응이 없어요
I got nothing.
그래, 착하지
Good chair.
누가 물으면
Now, if anybody asks...
넌 로지타야
your name is Rosita.
Poor thing. Cut down in her prime.
불쌍한 것
황금기에 가 버리다니
Joey, the new chair
will be here in an hour.
조이, 새 의자
한 시간 후면 올 거야
로지타를 옮겨야
되지 않겠니?
Maybe we should move
Rosita out of here.
마음을 굳게 먹어야지
Start the healing process.
그래, 네 말이 옳아
Yeah, I guess you're right.
다 나았어!
She's healed!
That's weird.
- 이상하네
- 이상한게 아냐
No, it's not weird.
기적이야!
It's a miracle!
기적은 무슨...
뭔가 이유가 있을 거야
It's not a miracle. I'm sure
there's an explanation.
있지, 마음이 순수하면
놀라운 일이 생기는 법이야
There is. If your heart is pure,
wondrous things can happen.
이해할 거야
일부러 그런 게 아니잖아
She'll understand.
I didn't do it on purpose.
Dad, that won't matter to her.
그게 문제가 아니에요
Look, all my stuff is safe and dry.
제건 다 안전한데
And all her stuff is...
모니카 것만 전부
growing new stuff.
곰팡이가 피었잖아요
This is the kind of thing...
이러니까 모니카가
that makes her think
you love me more than her.
아버지가 저만
좋아한다고 생각하잖아요
My God. Does she think that?
정말 그렇게 생각하니?
Well, can you blame her?
- 탓할 수도 없죠
- 글쎄다
We may have favored you unconsciously.
You were a marvel.
무의식적으론 그랬을 지도
모르지, 넌 기적이었어
-The doctors said your mom couldn't..
-I don't want to hear it.
- 의사 말론 네 엄마가...
- 그 얘긴 듣기 싫어요
- 진심이니?
- 지금은요
-Really?
-Well, not right now.
모니카도 추억거릴 찾아 왔는데
뭔가를 줘야죠
Monica came here for some memories.
Damn it, we'll give her some.
좋아요
Okay, grab...
박스 좀 줘 봐요
내 물건 중에서
Grab some boxes. We'll take stuff
from mine...
- 모니카 것이 될 만한 걸 찾죠
- 그래
and whatever we can pass off
as hers, we'll put in there.
이런 거, 그럴듯하죠?
Like, this. She could have made this.
- 이것도 마찬가지고
- 네
-This could have been hers.
-Sure.
If you want to tell the medical marvel
story while we work, that'd be fine.
이젠 제가 의학적 기적으로
태어났던 얘기 하셔도 되요
I am so psyched
I kept this chair for myself.
이 의자 내가 가지게 돼서
너무 신난다
Yeah. Me too.
그래, 나도
여기 머리받이에
스피커도 있는 거 알아?
You know, this thing has
speakers in the headrest?
- 정말이야?
- 그럼
-No, really?
-Yeah.
TV에 연결해도 되고
라디오도 들을 수 있어
You can hook it to the TV
and you get radio.
내 의잔 저절로 나았어
My chair heals itself.
좋아요, 사무실
사람들은 그렇다치고
All right. Let's just forget about
the people at the office, okay?
삶의 주변에 누군가
있을 거 아니에요
There's gotta be someone
worth sticking around for.
가족이나 친구는요?
아님 여자친구라도?
What about family or friends?
Maybe a girlfriend?
Yeah, right.
그만 하쇼
Oh, sorry. Boyfriend?
미안해요,
남자친구라도?
그럼 난 이만
Okay, I should...
내 일이나 해야겠네요
be getting back to my thing now.
그럼
See you.
내 말 안 끝났어요!
끊지 말아요!
I'm not finished!
Don't you dare hang up on me!
새로온 아가씨
잘 하는데
The new girl's good.
내 상자 어디 있어요?
Which boxes are mine?
- 여기 있는 상자들이야
- 그래
-These are yours right here.
-Okay.
색칠 공부책
A coloring book.
아주 좋아했잖아
You loved that thing.
어딜 가든 항상
그 색칠 공부책을
You never went anywhere without...
들고 다녔지
without that coloring book.
정말?
Really?
보니까 제대로 칠한 게
하나도 없네
Looks like I had trouble
staying in the lines.
그럴 리가!
Nuh-uh!
Wow, look at this.
와, 이 것 좀 봐요
I can't believe I even
fit into this shirt.
이 셔츠가 나한테
맞았다니 믿을 수가 없네
티라노사우르스
'로스'
Oh, this is yours.
이건 오빠 거네
I don't know how that got in there.
그게 왜 거기 있지?
Hey, this isn't my stuff.
이건 내 상자가 아니네
Ross, these are your boxes.
이 거 다 오빠 거야
Where are my boxes?
내 상자 어디 있어요?
네 상자는 차고에 물이 찼을 때
다 젖었단다, 미안해
The garage flooded, sweetie,
and ruined your boxes. I'm sorry.
Just mine?
내 거만요?
I'm afraid so.
그렇게 됐다
Why wasn't Ross' stuff ruined?
오빠 물건은 왜 멀쩡해요?
포르셰에 물 못 들어가게
막느라 네 상자를 썼다
I used your boxes to divert
water away from the Porsche.
Ross' stuff is fine,
but I have no memories...
오빠 건 괜찮고
내 추억은 다 사라졌네요
so you could keep the bottom
of your car from water?
아빠 차에 물 안 차게
하느라고요!
There was also
leaves and gook and stuff.
물 말고 나뭇잎이나
오물도 있었어
I can't believe this!
기가 막혀!
Screw it. I'm having one.
젠장, 한 대 피워야겠다
-Hey, Chandler.
-Hey.
- 챈들러
- 안녕
뒤로 젖혀지고
마사지 기능도 있고
How'd you like to sit
in a chair that reclines...
스피커도 달린
has a rolling massage...
의자에 한 번 앉아 볼래?
and speakers in the headrest?
너무 자주 갔더니
I've tried that so many times...
이젠 가게에서
못 오게 하더라
they won't even let me
in the store anymore.
내 아파트에서 할 수 있다면?
What if I said you could
do it in my apartment?
네 말은
다른 의자들을
Are you telling me...
초라하게 만드는
의자를 샀다는 거야?
you bought the chair
that makes all others obsolete?
잡지에서 '올해의 의자'로
뽑힌 그 의자를?
The chair that Sit Magazine called
"Chair of the Year"?
내가 방금
I just purchased...
레이지보이 이클라이너
3000을 구입했지
the La-Z-Boy E-Cliner 3000.
와, 죽인다!
의잔 갑자기 왜 산 거야?
Well, that's awesome! That's great!
What made you do it?
얘기하자면 긴데
내가 조이 의자를 부셔서...
It's a long story, but,
I broke Joey's chair..
네가 조이 의자를
부셨다고?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You broke Joey's chair?
난 내가 그런 줄 알고
내 것과 바꿔놨는데
I thought I did, that's why
I replaced it with mine.
그래서 멀쩡했구나
That's how it got fixed!
그럼 요정이라도 와서
고친 줄 알았어?
You thought that elves
came in and fixed it?
아니
No.
천사가
Angels.
의자 도로 가져와야지
I'm getting my chair back.
봤더니 고쳐진 게
아니었더라고!
Well, looks like
it wasn't healed after all!
이제 이 의자 내 거야
I guess this chair's mine now.
네가 내 의자를 부셨어!
Joey, you broke my chair!
네 의자?
Your chair?
챈들러가 자기가 부순 줄
알고 바꿔 놓은 거래
He thought he broke it,
so he switched chairs.
그럼 기적이 아니었어?
So there was no miracle?
아니, 기적이 아냐
No, Joe. No miracle.
이런! 어쩌면 좋지?
Oh, no! This is devastating!
믿음이 흔들리네, 새 의자가
있어 상심은 덜 하지만
My faith is shaken. I'm glad I have
a new chair to get me through this.
실례, 얼 어디 있어요?
구매담당자거든요
Where can I find Earl?
He's the supply manager here.
I don't know any Earl.
얼이란 사람 몰라요
I'm right here!
나 여기 있잖아요!
Earl?
얼?
I'm Phoebe.
피비예요
Phoebe?
피비?
The lady who sells toner?
토너 파는 아가씨요?
Look, you can't kill yourself.
자살하면 안 되요
Look, I really appreciate
you coming down..
여기까지 와준 건
고맙지만...
No, I can't let you do it.
죽게 놔둘 순 없어요
-Why?
-Because, fate made me call you today.
- 왜요?
- 내가 전화한 건 운명 때문이죠
I thought it was toner.
토너가 아니고요?
Think about it, okay?
This isn't even my regular job.
잘 생각해 봐요
이게 원래 내 일도 아니고
My first day, you're my first call.
출근 첫 날에
댁이 첫 고객이었죠
Somebody else may have hung up,
but I wouldn't do that...
다른 사람이라면 끊었겠지만
난 안 끊었어요
because I know about this stuff.
이 방면엔 전문가거든요
-My mom killed herself.
-Really?
- 우리 엄마도 자살하셨어요
- 정말이에요?
How?
- 어떻게요?
- 그대로 따라하려고요?
I'm not gonna give you tips.
Don't you see that this...
다 내가 그 쪽 자살을
all came together so I could
stop you from doing this?
막으려고 일이 이렇게
된 거 모르겠어요?
-Couldn't it just be a coincidence?
-No, it's fate.
- 그냥 우연이 아니고요?
- 아뇨, 운명이에요
It doesn't really seem like
enough to be fate.
운명이라고 하기엔
뭔가가 부족해요
Oh, well.
글쎄요
Okay, here's a weird thing.
이상한 게 또 있어요
My mother was also a supply manager.
엄마도 구매 담당자였어요
사실 난 사무실 매니저요
I'm actually the office manager.
어머나! 우리 엄마도요!
Oh, my God! So was she!
And get this, okay.
그리고 이 것도요
Your name is Earl, right?
Her name was Pearl.
그 쪽 이름이 얼이죠?
엄마 이름이 펄이거든요
Puh-Earl.
퍼-얼
Was there anything else?
또 없어요?
Sure.
있죠
고향이 어디예요?
Where're you from?
- 필라델피아
- 우리 엄마도요!
-Philadelphia.
-Oh, my God, so was she!
소름돋는 것 봐요
I've got goose bumps.
Really?
- 그래요?
- 옷을 많이 입고 더워서...
I'm wearing layers, and it's warm.
이 사람들은 어떨지 몰라도
These jerks might not care about you...
전 우주가 당신에게
관심을 보이고 있어요
but the universe does,
and that says a lot.
들었어요?
Did you hear that?
댁들이 신경
안 써줘도 괜찮아
I don't need you guys
to care about me...
우주가 관심을 보이니까!
because the universe cares!
전 우주가 말야!
The whole universe!
그래도 조금은
관심을 보이면 좋겠는데
I really wish they'd care
a little bit.
Oh, this is terrible.
정말 너무해
Everything is destroyed.
모든 게 망가졌어
Look at this.
이것 좀 봐
It meant enough for me to save,
and now I can't tell what it is.
아끼는 거니까 보관했을 텐데
알아보지도 못 하겠다
It's still soft.
아직도 부드러워
What do you think this is?
이게 뭘 것 같아?
I think it was a mouse.
쥐 같은데
-How are you, honey?
-How do you think I am?
- 좀 어떠니, 얘야?
- 어떨 것 같아요?
You've wrecked my childhood memories...
어린 시적 추억은
사라지고
you love Ross more than me.
아빤 오빠만 좋아하고
And I just rubbed
a dead mouse on my face.
방금 죽은 쥐를
얼굴에 비볐다고요
Sweetheart, we love you
just as much as Ross.
얘야, 너도 로스만큼
사랑한단다
I'm sorry about what happened...
이렇게 돼서 미안하고
and I probably can't
make it up to you...
어떤 식으로도
보상이 안 되겠지만
이거 받아라
but here's a start.
- 이게 뭐예요?
- 내 포르셰 열쇠다
-What's this?
-It's the key to my Porsche.
이젠 네 포르셰지
Well, the key to your Porsche.
네?
What?
What?!
I've considered getting rid of it.
I saw my reflection the other day.
안 그래도 팔려고 했다
내 모습을 거울로 보니...
Your mother's right,
I do look like an ass.
엄마 말이 옳았어
꼴불견이더구나
나한테 주신다고요?
농담이시죠?
You're giving it to me?
You're kidding.
잠깐만요
Well, wait a minute.
보잘것 없는 상자 몇 개
버렸다고 포르셰를 줘요?
A couple of stupid boxes get wet,
and she gets a Porsche?
- 드라이브 갈까?
- 좋아요!
-Let's take a drive?
-All right!
저는요?
의학적 기적이라면서요!
What about me? I'm a medical marvel!
얘들아
Hey, guys.
챈들러 의자 못 봤어?
Have you seen Chandler's chair?
조이가 부숴서 갖다 버렸어
Joey broke it. He got rid of it.
정말? 포르셰도 생기고
그 의자도 없어지고
Are you kidding? I get a Porsche
and the Barcalounger's gone?
This is the best day ever!
내 일생 최고의 날이다!